Finding Aid for the Kenneth Macgowan Papers LSC.0887
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Motion Picture Production Files
  - Production Files of Various Motion Pictures Kenneth Macgowan Produced or Was Associated With
    - Murder on the Blackboard, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Material re the motion picture including correspondence, ephemera and photographs. v.p., 1934.; 46 items. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Music Man tentative title The Waltz King, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Story synopsis for the motion picture. n.p., 1933.; 2 items. Typescript (carbon) (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Penguin Pool Murder, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1932.; 32 items. Typescript, printed and photograph. (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Rafter Romance, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1933.; 22 items. Typescript, printed and photograph. (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - The Return of Peter Grimm, RKO Radio Pictures, Incorporated (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1935.; 47 items. (Box 34, Folder 10)
        Including ephemera, photographs, and production sheets.
    - This is My Affair, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1936-1937.; 56 items. (Box 35, Folder 1)
        Including clippings, photographs, and correspondence.
      - Story treatments titled Turn of the Century. n.p., August 1936.; 2 items. Typescript (carbon). (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - This is My Affair. (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Story treatments for the motion picture titled The McKinley Case. n.p., May-June 1936.; 4 items. Typescript (carbon) and mimeograph. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Tin Pan Alley, Twentieth Century-Fox, Incorporated (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Material re the motion picture., 11 items. Typescript (carbon) and printed. (Box 35, Folder 4)
        Including correspondence.
    - To Mary With Love, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence and clippings re the motion picture. v.p., 1935-1936.; 34 items. Typescript and printed. (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Material re the music for the motion picture. v.p., 1936.; 5 items. Typescript and mimeograph. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - To Mary With Love. (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Photographs of scenes from the motion picture. Hollywood, 1936.; 20 items. Black and white. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Wake Up and Live, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1936-1937.; 19 items. (Box 35, Folder 8)
        Including clippings and correspondence.
    - Wake Up and Live. (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Photographs of scenes from the motion picture. Hollywood, 1937.; 19 items. Black and white. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Young Mr. Lincoln, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1938-1939.; 33 items. (Box 35, Folder 10)
        Including photocopies of sets, correspondence, and production reports.
      - Clippings, advertisements, and pamphlets re the motion picture. v.p., 1939.; 21 items. Printed. (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Young Mr. Lincoln. (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Picture estimate for the motion picture. Los Angeles, 1939.; 24 leaves. (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Photographs of scenes from the motion picture. Hollywood, 1939.; 30 items. Black and white. (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Lifeboat, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation. (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence re the motion picture. v.p., 1943-1945.; 20 leaves. Typescript (mostly carbon) and 1 ephemera. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Lifeboat. (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - A radio impression by Milton Geiger. New York, 1943.; 11 leaves. Typescript. (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Photographs of scenes from the motion picture. Beverly Hills, 1943.; 5 items. Black and white. (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Clippings from newspapers and periodicals re the motion picture. v.p., 1943-1944.; 21 items. (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Picture estimate and other records re the motion picture. Los Angeles, 1943.; 4 items. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Lloyds of London, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence re the motion picture. v.p., 1936-1938.; 27 leaves. Typescript (much carbon) and holograph. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Lloyds of London. (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Records and reports re the motion picture. Hollywood, 1936-1937.; 5 items. (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Clippings, advertisements, booklets and research material re the motion picture. v.p., v.d.; 28 items. Printed. (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Photocopies of drawings of scenes from the motion picture. Hollywood, 1936.; 49 items. (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Photographs of scenes from the motion picture. Hollywood, 1936.; 44 items. Black and white. (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Picture estimates for the motion picture. Los Angeles, 1936.; 2 items. (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Love and Hisses, Twentieth Century-Fox Corporation (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - Material re the motion picture. v.p., 1937-1938.; 25 items. (Box 36, Folder 12)
        Including correspondence, ephemera, records and photographs.
- Clippings from Newspapers and Periodicals, Ephemera and Other Material
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbooks belonging to Kenneth Macgowan of clippings re the theatre. v.p., 1908-1914.; 2 items. Printed. (Box 37)
    - Scrapbooks belonging to Kenneth Macgowan of clippings re the theatre. v.p., 1914-1918.; 2 items. Printed. (Box 38)
    - Scrapbooks belonging to Kenneth Macgowan of clippings re the theatre. v.p., 1914-1918.; 2 items. Printed. (Box 39)
  - Ephemera re Motion Pictures in Various Countries
    - Great Britain. Ephemera re motion pictures in Great Britain. v.p., v.d.; Approximately 90 items. (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Great Britain. Ephemera re motion pictures in Great Britain. v.p., v.d.; 6 items. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - China and Japan. Ephemera re motion pictures in China and Japan. v.p., v.d.; ca. 45 items. (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - France. Ephemera re motion pictures in France. v.p., v.d.; ca. 50 items. (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Germany. Ephemera re motion pictures in Germany. v.p., v.d.; ca. 20 items. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - India and Pakistan. Ephemera re motion pictures in India and Pakistan. v.p., v.d.; 8 items. (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Italy. Ephemera re motion pictures in Italy. v.p., v.d.; ca. 45 items. (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Scandinavian countries. Ephemera re motion pictures in Scandinavian countries. v.p., v.d.; ca. 23 items. (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Soviet countries. Ephemera re motion pictures in Soviet countries. v.p., v.d.; ca. 25 items. (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, notes, etc. re movies and television as a media for advertising. v.p., v.d.; ca. 45 items. (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous advertisements, announcements, brochures, mailers, etc. v.p., v.d.; ca. 35 items. (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous advertisements, announcements, brochures, mailers, etc. v.p., v.d.; ca. 30 items. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Ephemera re Motion Pictures
    - Animation, motion pictures. Ephemera re animation. v.p., v.d.; ca. 50 items. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Censorship of motion pictures. Ephemera. v.p., v.d.; 47 items. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Censorship of motion pictures. Ephemera. v.p., v.d.; ca. 26 items. (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Copyrights and royalties in motion pictures. v.p., v.d.; 1 item. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Documentary films. Ephemera. v.p., v.d.; ca. 35 items. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Dubbing in films. Ephemera. v.p., v.d.; 32 items. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Material re the Educational Film Research Institute. v.p., v.d.; 24 items. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Museum of Modern Art Film Library. New York, 1940-1959.; 20 items. (Box 41, Folder 8)
      Material re the Museum library, including correspondence and pamphlets.
    - Basic principles of the three dimensional film. Journal of the Society of Motion Picture Television Engineers. England, 1952.; ca. 75 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Ephemera re Education and Motion Pictures
    - Material re education and films. v.p., v.d.; 23 items. Ephemera and pamphlets. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Material re education and films. v.p., v.d.; 7 items. Ephemera and pamphlets. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Material re education and films. v.p., v.d.; 15 items. Ephemera and pamphlets. (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Macgowan, Kenneth, 1888-1963. Making the screen a better blackboard. Los Angeles, 1948.; ca. 60 leaves. Typescript. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Palmer, Charles. The reluctant miracle. n.p., Sept. 9-11, 1947.; 14 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Rejlek, Frantisek. A study of the use of film in science. Los Angeles, June 1949.; 128 leaves. Typescript. (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - The American Museum of Natural History. Correspondence. v.p., 1954-1955.; 10 items. Typescript. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Government and motion pictures. Material re education and films. v.p., v.d.; 7 items. Ephemera and typescript. (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - International Film Foundation. Material re education and films. v.p., 1946.; 3 items. (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Teaching Films Corporation. Material re education and films. New York, 1946-1947.; 8 items. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Ephemera re Motion Pictures, Radio, and Television
    - Ephemera concerning motion pictures and T.V. and their relationship to children. v.p., v.d.; 8 items. (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Ephemera concerning motion pictures and T.V. re children. v.p., v.d.; 6 items. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Clippings about newsreels. v.p., v.d.; 4 items. (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Clippings and notes about westerns. v.p., v.d.; 24 items. (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Material re the motion picture Boundary Lines. v.p., 1947-1950.; 15 items. Ephemera, mimeograph, Typescript (carbon). (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Clipped articles and other ephemera re motion pictures. v.p., v.d.; 38 items. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Clipped articles and other ephemera re motion pictures. v.p., v.d.; 20 items. (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Brochures and pamphlets re various aspects of motion pictures. v.p., v.d.; 14 items. (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Clippings and other ephemera re motion picture companies diversification of interests. v.p., 1946-1960.; ca. 65 items. (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Clippings re radio and television. v.p., v.d.; 8 items. (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Clippings re television. v.p., 1943-1957.; 62 items. (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Clippings and other ephemera re television. v.p., 1958-1962.; 61 items. (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Clippings and other ephemera re television, v.p., v.d.; ca. 50 items. (Box 43, Folder 13)
      Includes many fragments.
  - Theater Programs, Posters, Miscellaneous Material re Government and Politics
    - Theatre programs and other ephemera from Macgowan's sabbatical trip to Denmark and England., 1953-1954.; 34 items. (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Theatre programs and other pamphlets from Macgowan's sabbatical trip to France and Germany., 1953-1954.; 11 items. (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Theater and other programs. v.p., v.d.; 26 items. (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Theater programs and posters in languages other than English. v.p., v.d.; 5 items. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Posters in some way re Kenneth Macgowan. v.p., v.d.; 3 items. (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Booklets, pamphlets and periodicals re government and politics. v.p., v.d.; 7 items. (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Tulane drama review. New Orleans, Louisiana, 1965-1966. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Ephemera, Pamphlets, and Books
    - Ephemera re the New York Drama League. New York, 1918-1920.; 38 items. (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Ephemera re Theater Arts Magazine, New York, Also included are two issues., 1919-1922.; 27 items. (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Drama survey; a review of dramatic literature and the theatrical arts. Minnesota, 1962 and 1964.; 3 issues. (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous booklets and little magazines re theater. v.p., v.d.; 6 items. (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Pamphlets re drama and the theater. v.p., v.d.; 6 items. (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlets re motion pictures. v.p., v.d.; 2 items. (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous booklets, pamphlets, and brochures on various subjects. v.p., v.d.; 13 items. (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous booklets, pamphlets, and brochures on various subjects. v.p., v.d.; 7 items. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - The Evening Ledger, March 1915-March 1916
    - The Evening Ledger. Whole newspapers and various sections, some with articles by K. Macgowan. Philadelphia, March-October 1915.; 10 items. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - The Evening Ledger., December 1915.; 4 items. (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - The Evening Ledger., December 1915.; 9 items. (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - The Evening Ledger., January 1916.; 5 items. (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - The Evening Ledger., January 8-31, 1916.; 7 items. (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - The Evening Ledger., February 1916.; 7 items. (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - The Evening Ledger., March 1916.; 6 items. (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - The Evening Ledger. Whole newspapers and various sections, some with articles by K. Macgowan. Philadelphia, April 1916.; 8 items. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - The Evening Ledger. Whole newspapers and various sections, some with articles by K. Macgowan. Philadelphia, May 1916.; 6 items. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - The Evening Ledger., June-Sept., 1916.; 6 items. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - The Evening Ledger., October 1916.; 8 items. (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - The Evening Ledger., November 1916.; 4 items. (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - The Evening Ledger., December 1916.; 5 items. (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - The Evening Ledger., January 1917.; 9 items. (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Whole Newspapers re World War I, and World War II
    - Whole newspapers re the end of World War I. New York, November 7, 1918.; 2 items. (Duplicates). (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
    - Whole newspapers re the end of World War I. New York, November 11, 1918.; 3 items. (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Whole newspapers re the end of World War II. Los Angeles, 1944 (June 6) and February 5-April 6, 1945.; 5 items. (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Whole newspapers re the end of World War II. Los Angeles and New York, April 13-May 5, 1945.; 5 items. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Articles Clipped from Newspapers and Periodicals, Written by Kenneth Macgowan
    - Articles clipped from newspapers and periodicals written by Kenneth Macgowan. v.p., 1905-1913.; 64 items. (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., 1914-1916.; 19 items. (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., 1917.; 9 items. (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers... v.p., January-June 1918.; 17 items. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., July-December 1918.; 54 items. (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Reprints of newspaper articles written by K. Macgowan. New York, 1918.; 4 items. (Duplicates). (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., 1919.; 22 items. (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., January- April 1920.; 22 items. (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers and periodicals, written by K. Macgowan. v.p., May-December 1920.; 42 items. (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers..... v.p., January-April 1921.; 15 items. (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., May-December 1921.; 29 items. (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., January-September 1922.; 29 items. (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., October-December 1922.; 56 items. (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., January-April 1923.; 75 items. (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., May-December 1923.; 34 items. (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., 1924-1929.; 19 items. (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Articles clipped from newspapers.... v.p., 1930-1963.; 32 items. (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Whole magazines with articles written by Kenneth Macgowan. v.p., v.d.; 5 items. (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Clipped, undated articles on various subjects written by K. Macgowan. Subjects: art, motion pictures, and miscellaneous., 11 items. (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Clipped, undated articles about the theatre, written by K. Macgowan., 96 items. (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Clipped, undated articles about the theatre, written by K. Macgowan., 27 items. (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Clipped, undated articles about the theatre, written by K. Macgowan., ca. 30 items (Includes fragments and 1 correspondence). (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Articles Clipped from Newspapers and Periodicals Referring to Kenneth Macgowan and His Works
    - Articles clipped from newspapers and periodicals referring to Kenneth Macgowan, and his works. v.p., 1919-1966.; 74 items. (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Clipped articles in languages other than English referring to K. Macgowan. v.p., v.d.; 4 items, plus 1 translation. (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Clippings re Behind the Screen. Los Angeles, 1965.; 1 item. (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Clippings re Continental Stagecraft. v.p., 1922.; 16 items. (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Clippings re Continental Stagecraft. v.p., 1923.; 80 items. (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Clippings re Footlights Across America. v.p., 1929-1930.; ca. 85 items. (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and a few letters re The Theatre of Tomorrow. v.p., 1921-1923.; ca. 85 items. (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Material re Theatre Pictorial. v.p., 1954.; 12 items. (Box 52, Folder 8)
      Includes ephemera and correspondence.
    - Clippings re books on marriage written by K. Macgowan and G. Hamilton. v.p., 1929.; ca. 50 items. (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Dust jackets for various books by K. Macgowan., 4 items. (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera referring to K. Macgowan., 2 items. (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, Ephemera, Photographs and Books on Motion Picture and Theatre, etc.
    - Clippings from newspapers and periodicals about St. John Ervine. v.p., 1924.; 5 items. (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Clippings about Lawrence Langner's play Modern Women. New York, ca. 1928.; 6 items. (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous clippings about theater and motion pictures. v.p., 1917-1937.; 23 items. (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous clippings about theater and motion pictures. v.p., 1938-1963.; 20 items. (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous clippings about motion pictures and theatre. v.p., 30 items. (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous articles about theater in India. v.p., v.d.; 3 items. (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera re Korean drama. v.p., v.d.; 4 items. (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous clippings on various subjects. v.p., v.d.; ca. 50 items. (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous clippings in languages other than English. v.p., v.d.; 7 items. (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera and fragments. v.p., v.d.; 9 items. (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous photographs re motion pictures, theatre, and various productions. v.p., v.d.; 30 items. (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous photographs of various subjects and picture postcards., 45 items. (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous drawings re theater. n.p., n.d.; 6 items. (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous books and little magazines by various authors of plays, poetry, and literature in German, Spanish and English., 6 items. (Box 53, Folder 13)
- Activities as an Educator
  - Material re Macgowan's Rockefeller Foundation Grant
    - Notes on the Turkish Theatre, by K. Macgowan. Published in Drama Survey, Minneapolis, Minnesota., Winter 1962.; 7 items. (Box 54, Folder 1)
      Includes manuscript.
    - Miscellaneous material re the Turkish State Theatre., 6 items. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Notes on the Turkish Theatre by K. Macgowan. Published in Drama Survey, Minneapolis, Minnesota, Winter 1962.; 2 items. (2 issues). (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Various articles about Turkey by Macgowan. Manuscript material and related correspondence. v.p., 1961.; 17 items. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous manuscript material re Turkey by K. Macgowan., 7 items. (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence of Macgowan and the Rockefeller Foundation re his trip to Turkey. v.p., 1956-1958.; ca. 75 items. (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Material re the students of K. Macgowan in Turkey. Ankara, Includes résumés, photos, etc., 1958.; 50 items. (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Ephemera re Kenneth Macgowan's Rockefeller Foundation Grant to Turkey
    - Correspondence re Macgowan's teaching in Turkey. v.p., 1957-1961.; 32 items. (Box 55, Folder 1)
      Includes enclosures. A - M.
    - Correspondence re Macgowan's teaching in Turkey. v.p., 1957-1961.; 39 items. (Box 55, Folder 2)
      N - Z.
    - Correspondence re Macgowan's teaching in Turkey with Batur, Sevgi., 20 items. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Refik Erduran re Macgowan's teaching in Turkey., 28 items. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Ifran Sahinbas re Macgowan's teaching in Turkey., 22 items. (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Nureddin Sevin re Macgowan's teaching in Turkey., 15 items. (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, lists, and notes re Macgowan's trip to Turkey. Los Angeles, 1958.; ca. 30 items. (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re articles by Macgowan about Turkey and the Turkish Theatre. v.p., 1958-1961.; 40 items. (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Clippings and other material re Turkey and Magowan's trip to Turkey. v.p., 1957-1962.; ca. 40 items. (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Ephemera re the Turkish theater., 9 items. (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Theater Programs and Photographs of Theatrical Productions in Turkey
    - Photographs of Turkey and of scenes from theatrical productions in Turkey including postcards., 58 items. (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Turkish theater programs., 1957-1959.; 10 items. (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Turkish theater programs., 1960.; 4 items. (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Turkish theater programs., 1961.; 5 items. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Turkish theater programs., 1962.; 4 items. (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Turkish theater programs., 1963-1964 and n.d.; 8 items. (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Turkish theater programs., 1965-1966.; 12 items. (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Ephemera re Harvard University
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous manuscripts, notes and fragments, etc. re Harvard University. v.p., 1931-1962.; ca. 45 items. (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Autobiographical article by Macgowan re education at Harvard. Los Angeles, 1936.; 9 leaves (Also included are some personal records from Harvard). (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Clippings and other ephemera re Harvard, some referring to Macgowan. v.p., 1911-1962.; 20 items. (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, ephemera, and manuscripts re the annual Theodore Spehcer Lecture at Harvard.... given by Macgowan. v.p., 1957.; 12 items. (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous leaves of manuscript of the text of the Spencer Lecture. Los Angeles, 1957.; ca. 80 leaves. Typescript (mostly carbon). (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous leaves of manuscript of the text of the Spencer Lecture., ca. 50 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Ephemera re Harvard including momentos of Macgowan's Harvard days. v.p., 1909-1949.; 13 items. (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous articles by Macgowan that appeared in Harvard publications. Cambridge, Massachusetts, v.d.; 7 items. (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Various Harvard periodical publications., 1936-1956.; 10 items. (Box 57, Folder 9)